Curriculum Vitae

George Onisiforou

Having worked for over 6 years in the Shipping industry, I re-routed my career back to my original bachelor's degree, Computer Science. With a main focus and interest in Web Development, I am looking forward to helping teams build their projects and conquer the Web.

13 Rodiona Georgiadi street Limassol, CY 4001 Date of Birth: 29/07/1990

+357 99921580

georgeon@hotmail.com

Website:

https://www.georgeonisiforou.com/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TIO Markets Ltd - Front-end Developer

December 2022 - now

Involvement in the major restructuring of the company's website with modern technologies. Support and maintenance of webpages and implementation of new landing pages. Regular communication with the marketing department and web designers for the most accurate implementation of the website's design. Participation in various internal company projects and applications and experimentation with several technologies.

- Javascript / React / Next.js
- CSS / Styled Components
- Git / Github
- Sanity

VASLABS LTD - Software Engineer Intern

June 2022 - August 2022

Introduction and daily training with various technologies. Daily completion of assignments and GitHub issues. Implementation and presentation of a personal project in the last 3 weeks. Active participation in open source projects. Technologies and concepts used:

- Scala / Functional programming
- Docker / Terraform
- Git / Github
- Node.js / TypeScript / React / Next.js / Markdown
- Bash
- Unit testing

SCF MANAGEMENT SERVICES (CYPRUS) LTD, - Freight Collection

December 2015 - May 2022

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | Next.js | TailwindCSS | Node.js | Sanity | Framer Motion | Styled components

Git | GitHub

Fast compilation of clear and understandable professional email messages

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Quick and keen learner

Ability to work under pressure and meet guidelines

Teamwork skills

Full clean Driving Licence

LANGUAGES

Greek (mother tongue), English (fluent)

Heavily involved throughout the invoicing procedure and timely

collection of receivables for a vessel's commercial Fixture achieved through constant communication and coordination with colleagues, Ship Brokers and Charterers. Specialization in the Tanker Market.

- Extensive knowledge in calculation of several costs
- Familiarity and understanding of Charter Party terms
- Proficient use of the Veslink IMOS platform
- Decision making tailored on a case by case approach
- Awareness of interconnection of workflow between various departments
- Reading and understanding supporting documents such as vessel certificates, port disbursements, statement of facts etc.

DPSS GLOBAL CONSULTANTS LTD — Business Development Officer

February 2015 - October 2015

EDUCATION

Institute of Chartered Shipbrokers — Professional Qualifying Examinations (PQE)

January 2016 - Present

Elected member since 2019.

BIMCO — Masterclass Workshop, Laytime & Demurrage

March 15 -17, 2017

Cardiff University, UK — Master of Science (MSc), Marine Policy

September 2013 - September 2014

Dissertation: "Integrating Social Media in the Supply Chain".

*Active member and among the founders of the Cardiff University Greek & Cypriot Society

University of Manchester, UK — B.Sc. (Hons.) Computer Science with Business Management

September 2010 - June 2013

Dissertation: "An eBook Generator for Learning Java".

INTERESTS

I thoroughly enjoy travelling whenever possible.

Football fan and passionate Liverpool F.C. supporter

Exercising

Eating and socializing with friends

Concerts and good music

Gardening

REFERENCES

Available upon request.